Guide to the Hospitality Leadership: The Cornell Hotel School research papers, 1920-1999.
Hospitality Leadership The Cornell Hotel School research papers
- "Trouble Checks in at Statler" / "Dean Announces New Academic Affairs Team" / others, Various; Multi-format, Copy No. of pieces: 7 (Box 4, Folder 366)
  Additional description: 09/05/1995; 08/27/1995; 06/16/1995; 10/25/1990; 04/12/1990; 05/22/1990; 05/17/1990. Letter regarding revisements needed on the Clark chapter. / News article reviewing the service at Statler Hotel. / Press release announcing academic affairs team and faculty promotions. / Letter of explanation as to why there needs to be a 28.5 mortgage placed on Statler project. / Letter about replacement wall covering. / Letter about request for Priscilla Noetzel-Wilson to be construction manager on Auditorium Project. / Notes on Auditorium progress.
  Author: Dittman, David / Reynolds, Christopher / Adams, Mark / Dittman, David / Peckenpaugh, Norm / Griffen, Paul / Unknown
  Recipient: Chiu, Michael / None / None / Faculty and Alumni / Colclough, Breda / Keithan, Bill / Keithan, Bill
- "The 44th Hotel Ezra Cornell" / None / Sidebar Assignment Sheet, None; Multi-format, Copy No. of pieces: 3 (Box 4, Folder 367)
  Additional description: Beginning of article about the 44th HEC. / part of an interview. / writing assignments for the sidebars
- The Bulletin, Spring 1987 / Fall 1987; New Article, Copy No. of pieces: 2 (Box 4, Folder 368)
  Additional description: Hotel newsletter. Several articles about the renovations.
- Cornell University Faculty Information, 2/25/1957; Multi-format, Copy No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 369)
  Additional description: Information sheet on Gerald Lattin
- Obituaries of Thomas Silk, Frank Randolph, Matthew Bernatsky, and O. Earnest Banks. Notes on Beck, None; Letter, Copy No. of pieces: 5 (Box 4, Folder 370)
- Transcription of Dean Clark Interview, None; Multi-format, Copy No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 371)
  Additional description: Interview w/ Dean Clark, w/ appearances by Ted Kennedy and Dick Brown.
- Handwritten notes about Various topic, 1994; Multi-format, Original No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 372)
- Full Board Agenda Item, 5/30/1987; Multi-format, Copy No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 373)
  Additional description: Agenda explaining the budget increase for the Statler project, and budget tabulations.
- News articles about the Statler., Various; New Article, Copy No. of pieces: 19 (Box 4, Folder 374)
- Chapter six outline, Unknown; Multi-format, Copy No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 375)
  Additional description: Chapter six outline
- 2 letters are a back and forth between Clark and Griffen about blame for the Hotel project going over budget. 1 is regarding the response that Griffen sends Clark, 10/06/1989; 10/17/1989; 10/23/1989; Letter, Copy No. of pieces: 3 (Box 4, Folder 376)
  Author: Clark, John / Griffen, Paul / Clark, John
  Recipient: Griffen, Paul / Clark, John / deRoos, Jan; Peckenpaugh, Norm; Penner, Richard; Keithan, William
- "Hotel School to Teach Housing and Feeding of the Homeless", 11/18/1987; New Article, Copy No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 377)
  Additional description: Cornell University News article about a new course.
  Author: Kaff, Al
- Letter discussing Ithaca Fire Chief Olmstead's investigation of conditions on the Statler Hotel project, 5/20/1988; Letter, Copy No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 378)
  Author: Stewart, David
  Recipient: Burness, John
- Black & White Photos; one of Alice Statler breaking ground, one of Hotel school student cafeteria, one of Hotel Ezra Cornell students presenting cake to Pres. Deane Malott, 2 of two different classes., Various; Photograph, Original No. of pieces: 5 (Box 4, Folder 379)
  Additional description: 04/1956; 1953; 1958; 04/04/1945; 03/21/19??.
  Author: Unknown / Smith, Clayton / Malott, Deane / Unknown / Unknown
- School of Hotel Administration Course Enrollment / None / Hotel History / John J. Clark, Jr. / None, Various; Multi-format, Copy No. of pieces: 5 (Box 4, Folder 380)
  Additional description: Spring 1981; 10/15/1991; 05/15/1987; 10/?/1994; 04/26/1995. Copy of the course roster for spring 1981. / Letter outlining what is missing from the HH Book drafts. / Timeline history of the Hotel School. / History of John Clark and outline of major accomplishments. / Letter about Professor Kelly wanting to be involved w/ HH Book.
  Author: None / Keithan, William / Unknown / Unknown / Marcham, John
  Recipient: None / DeGraba, Sue / Unknown / Unknown / Brad
- "First Hotel Alumni Out Ten Years", 3/7/1995; New Article, Original No. of pieces: 1 (Box 4, Folder 381)
  Additional description: Old news article reprinted from the Cornell Alumni News about the first class to graduate from the Hotel School.
  Recipient: Cornell Alumni
- The Cornell Daily Sun: Various article titles, Various; New Article, Copy No. of pieces: 11 (Box 4, Folder 382)
  Additional description: Several articles about the Hotel demolition/renovation/opening, along w/ an article about Clark succeeding Beck as Dean
- Handwritten Hotel School anecdotes, Unknown / 10/23/1995; Letter, Copy No. of pieces: 2 (Box 4, Folder 383)
  Author: Kennedy, Richard / Watson, Roy
  Recipient: Unknown / Chiu, Michael
- All are letters w/ Hotel School anecdotes, Various; Letter, Copy No. of pieces: 4 (Box 4, Folder 384)
  Additional description: 10/28/1995; 10/29/1995; 10/03/1995; 10/11/1995.
  Author: Nelson, Richard / Rodriguez, Shirley / Eaton, William (2)
  Recipient: Chiu, Michael (all 4)
- "Life is Service" A History of the Cornell University School of Hotel Administration, No Date (Box 4, Folder 385)
- Various unidentified photographs of classrooms and people., Various; Letter, Copy No. of pieces: 4 (Box 5)
  Additional description: Includes: Group that took 1929 trip to New York First full class to graduate - 1926 Hotel Ambassadors - 1937 Class of 1931 Oscar Tschirky - Oscar of the Waldorf Menu from Professor Howard Meek's Retirement Party in Hawaii- 1961